(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
我不會找藉口.
MAN: I'm not gonna make excuses.
我是自願的
I asked ?or this.
所有的這一切
All of it.
(PANTING)
我這麼做是想變成其他人
And I did it to become someone else.
(CAR HORN BLARING)
我想要得到更多
I wanted more.
我們屬於看著我們的未來在眼皮底下溜走的那一代人
We belong to a generation that watched our future get stolen out from under us.
我們父輩崇尚的美國已經被那些
The American Dream our parents knew has been hijacked by men
為了保護他們財產而去撒謊 欺騙 盜竊的人們所劫持了.
who are willing to lie, cheat and steal to protect their wealth.
以前如果你有好的成績,你就可以進入好學校,
Used to be if you got good grades, you got into the right school,
得到一份不錯的工作.
got the rightjob.
然後經過 15年 左右的辛苦工作,
And after 15 years of hard work,
你在公司裏有了一定的地位
you get your name on the door.
但這樣的世界已不復存在了.
But that world is gone.
人們總是告誡你對自己的願望要謹慎.
People always tell you be careful what you wish for.
(EXHALES)
我再也不會相信他們說的話.
I never believed them.
河對岸的燈光總是很亮.
The lights always looked brighter across the river.
(PHONES RINGING)
快下來吧
Hey, come on!
我馬上來. 切爾.
Hey, I'm coming. Chill.
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
我需要付額外的錢嗎？
I'm paying extra for that?
別擔心,斯科特,這個是免費的
Don't worry, it's covered, Scout.
- 沒有東西是免費的,爸爸 - 你去哪?
- Nothing's covered, Dad. - Where you going?
我和卡維去酒吧.
I'm going to the club with Kev.
- 誰? - 別問了? 你又不認識他?
- Which one? - Why? You think you might know it?
在我年輕的時候我也常去迪斯可廳.
Well, I have been known to frequent discotheques in my heyday.
現在不這麼叫,但都一樣.
They don't call them that anymore, but that's good.
別讓他吸煙,他常把煙藏靠墊下.
Hey, don't let him smoke. He hides cigars under that cushion there.
不要吸了
Don't smoke!
有什麼關係,你嫉妒了？
What's the matter? You jealous?
你說對了
Oh, yes.
去RISE夜總會, 你怎麼這麼晚?
Club Rise, baby. What took you so long?
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYS)
請你幫個忙把繩子拿開
Why don't you do yourself a favor and lift the rope?
那你們又能幫到我什麼呢
And how is that doing me a favor?
考慮一下投資
Consider it an investment.
週一我跟我的小夥伴會再來的, 我們會賺到足夠的錢,
Come Monday, my boy and I wiii be making so much money,
你一定會求我們回來幫你的忙的
you'll be begging us to come back to this flavor of the month of yours.
看,沒有潮人,沒有處男.
Look, no hipsters and no virgins.
處男?
Virgin?
處男,他不是 ,我親眼看見他上床了
He's not a virgin. I just watched him get laid outside.
我真的親眼所見
I watched it, I literally saw him get laid.
- 艾登, 來吧. - 我親眼所見.
- Adam, come on. - I saw him with my own eyes.
我會回來的.
I'm going to be back.
- 你很緊張？
- (CAR HORN HONKS) - Are you nervous yet?
緊張? 為啥?
Nervous? About what?
週一我們要把產品展示給尼古拉斯·懷亞特這個怪胎, 這就是原因.
On Monday we pitch our product to Nicolas freaking Wyatt, that's what.
卡維, 我們為了這個產品忙了4個月,真是天才
Kevin, we've been working on that pitch for four months. It's genius.
我唯一擔心的是
The only thing I'm worried about is
懷亞特會炒誰魷魚來阻止我們的升職.
who Wyatt's gonna fire for not promoting us sooner.
用它來付賬單綽綽有餘
How great is it gonna be to pay our bills
並且負擔所有的衣食住行?
and eat in the same month?
準備好了嗎,好日子要開始了
Oh, get ready 'cause it's happening.
你總這麼說,可每次一無所獲還賠上計程車費.
You always say it's happening, and then I end up paying for the cab.
這次不同
This time's different.
這次的機會, 會改變我們的人生
This pitch, it's gonna change our lives.
我保證
Promise you.
但是還是要我付車費,對吧
But I'm still paying for the cab, right?
- 對- 趕緊付吧
- Yeah. - Got you.
- 不是我的.
- (CELL PHONE RINGS) - It's not me.
喂
Hello?
我已經在這兒了
Yeah, I'll be right there.
能拐一下嗎? 我們要去聖爵士醫院
Sir, can you turn around? We need to go to Saint Joe's Hospital.
艾登, 他幹的很好.
Adam, he's doing great.
他還在幹老本行,他剛好經過這兒
He's up to his old tricks. He's right through there.
醫生: 我們幫他清理了痰液,他很好.
DOCTOR: We cleared out the mucus, and he's fine.
但他必須更多的輸氧
But he must use the oxygen more,
阻塞時隨時叫我們
and he has to call us at the onset of congestion.
- 他知道 - 他希望自己來弄
- Yeah, he knows. - Wants to do it his own way, huh?
好吧
Yeah.
- 你可以帶他回家了, - 好的,謝謝.
- You can take him home. - All right. Thanks.
你看到了,凱斯蒂先生
As you can see, Mr. Cassidy,
最後兩個療程不能用保險支付
the last two procedures were not covered by insurance.
你的意思我需要額外付錢
What do you mean? I have extended coverage.
是的. 懷亞特公司已停止支付了.
You did. Wyatt Corp terminated it.
他們不應該那麼做,我應該有,需要這筆費用
They can't do that. I have it. I need to have it.
很不幸,他們有這個權利
Unfortunately, they can.
現在很多公司都這麼幹, 削減開支.
A iot of our companies are doing it now, cutbacks.
我沒有40塊
I don't have 40 grand.
我們可以提供一個支付計畫或醫療貸款.
We can help with a payment plan, or a medical loan.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
沒關係,我會有辦法的
Yeah. I'll figure something out.
我們已經盡力了,請理解
WOMAN: We did everything we could.
艾登: 我們為懷亞特公司賣命,
ADAM: We work for Wyatt Corp,
這個星球上一個頂級的科技公司.
one of the top tech companies on the planet.
(EXCITED CHATTERING)
當他們雇傭我們時,, 承諾我們將掌控世界.
When they hired us, we were going to take over the world.
但六年了, 我們還呆在小隔間裏,
Six years in, we were still just lowly cubicle drones,
看著老闆拿著高額薪金
watching our bosses take home obscene bonuses...
...我們只能拿可憐的底薪.
...while we were stuck with entrt-level salaries.
我們等了太久了,我們的機會該到了.
We'd waited long enough. It was our turn.
該我們光鮮的時代.
Our time to shine.
你還好嗎
KEVIN: You all right?
很好 我們要去搞定他了.
Yeah. We're gonna kill it.
如果事情便糟糕,要保持冷靜
Yeah, well, if things go south, just stay cooi. Aii right?
好吧
Yeah.
懷亞特先生準備好了.
Mr. Wyatt is ready.
保持冷靜
Stay cool.
早上好
Good morning.
我們都在做通信的生意
We are all in the business of connecting people.
這水不熱了
This water's not hot enough.
抱歉, 懷亞特先生. 我來處理吧
WOMAN: I'm sorry, Mr. Wyatt. I'll take care of it.
需要再加熱一下
It should be boiling.
喔... 我們都在做通信的研究.
Uh... We're in the business of connecting people.
你說過了
You already said that.
是的. 這正是我們的客戶要的,隨時保持聯絡暢通
Right. That's what our customers have always wanted. To stay connected.
同時是這些客戶發資訊超過了交談
Those same customers are now texting more than they're talking
發微博的時間超過了見面
and tweeting more than they're meeting.
是什麼改變了,我們錯過了什麼?
So, what's changed? What are we missing?
我們其實不要隨時保持線上.
We don't want to be connected anymore.
我們只是希望在孤獨的感覺到和外界有所聯絡.
We just want to feel connected whiie we isoiate.
因此...假如
So, what if...
...一個4英寸的手機有個60寸的螢幕?
...a four-inch mobile had a 60-inch screen?
- 那就是不是手機了.
- Well, then it wouldn't be mobile. - (LAUGHTER)
通過一個語音啟動的配對設備, Ethion APP將允許用戶
With a voice-activated pairing device, Ethion will allow users
將手機上的內容顯示在家中任何一台顯示器上.
to broadcast their mobile across any monitor in the home.
連線
Pick up.
Ethion 3.0 把整個世界帶到你的面前
Ethion 3.0 gives you the power to bring your world to you.
他在向我推銷軟體？
Is he pitching me software?
先生, 我們發現了絕佳的機會讓Ethion不僅僅運行在手機上...
Sir, we see a unique opportunity to take Ethion from a run-of-the-mill phone...
這是一個品牌再創的會議  兩者的聯繫在哪里
This is a re-branding meeting. Where's the disconnect?
哦, 先生, 我相信聯繫是在你跟消費者之間的
Well, sir, I believe the disconnect is between you and the consumers.
你雇我們肯定不是為看你沏茶,對吧?
You didn't hire us to sit around and watch you make tea, did you?
說說我為什麼要雇你
Tell me, why did I hire you?
因我們知道年輕一代要什麼
Because we know what a younger generation wants.
什麼呢
Which is?
並不僅僅是一部新手機
A phone that doesn'tjust iook new a phone that is new,
而是一部可以改變我們生活方式的手機
a phone that changes the way we live.
你是對的,我不瞭解你們這一代.
You know, you're right. I have lost touch with your generation.
對不起忘了你叫什麼名字
What was your name again?
艾登.凱斯帝.
I'm Adam Cassidy.
多大?
How old are you?
27.
Twenty-seven.
我比你年輕兩歲的時候,
When I was two years younger than you are now,
正在開發數位蜂窩技術
I was pioneering digital cellular technology
而我的室友還在擺弄電子脈衝.
whiie my coiieagues were stiii pissing around with electronic pulses.
我有遠見.
I had vision.
但是你只有科技觀點的想像力
But you have all the technological advantage imaginable
你帶給了我什麼?
and what do you bring me?
電視上的社交網路？
Social networking on a television.
下一個! 把理查·麥卡利斯特帶進來.
Next! Bring in Richard McAllister.
很抱歉.
I'm sorry, guys.
你只是讓我們想個傻子那樣站在那裏.
You just left us standing there looking like idiots.
你到底怎麼想的？
I mean, what were you thinking?
我們都支持這一理念.
We all backed the idea.
我們的理念不是問題 我惹怒了那個傢夥,你們都看到他的臉色了
Our idea wasn't the problem. I railroaded him. You saw his face.
假如你的團隊負責人瘋狂了,和上帝作對就會這樣.
That's what happens when your team leader goes rogue and argues with God.
唔 我猜現在我們不會一起工作了
Well, uh... I guess now that we're not working together
但我們還能一起睡覺當好基友 對不
we can start sieeping together, right?
我非常希望你是在開玩笑
I seriously hope you're not talking to me.
我們會找到新工作的,好嗎?
We'll find newjobs, right?
我們還不起債了,我們被解雇了.
KEVIN: We weren't laid off, Chels. We were fired.
你準備在簡歷上怎麼解釋?
How are you going to explain that on your resume?
你知道啥? 至少我可以請大家先喝杯飲料.
You know what? The least I can do is buy you guys a few drinks.
我們的自由帳戶?真的？
Our discretionary account? Really?
艾登, 不. 如果懷亞特一旦發現我們多花了錢...
Adam, no. If Wyatt ever found out that we spent any more money...
他們會怎麼做? 開除我們?
What are they going to do? Fire us?
錢我們花的適當就行,我們去RISE夜總會
The money was ours to spend as we see fit. We're going to Rise.
- 我們進不去 - 我們可以.
- We can't get in there. - Yes, we can.
- 我們可以. - 阻止那傢伙.
- Yes, we can. - Try and stop the guy.
($ EMPIRE OF THE SUN: "ALIVE (ZEDD REMIX)")
(HORNS HONKING)
我們要去RISE , 寶貝! 太棒了!
We're going to Rise, baby! Oh, yeah!
夥計,這簡直太酷了.
Dude, you realize this is going to be so awesome.
- 我們將會嗨爆全場. - 你也這樣覺得?
- We're going to pop ten bottles. - Think so?
我討厭那個看門的.
I hate this doorman.
艾登. 告訴你我會再來的.
Adam Cassidy. Told you I'd be back.
你們的入場券在這邊,先生.
Your table's right this way, sir.
- 太好了!
- Yeah! - (SQUEALING)
- 哦- 太棒了
- Yeah! - Oh!
- 倒酒!倒酒! - 倒酒!倒酒!
- Shots! - Shots!
- 倒酒!倒酒! - 我的天啊.
- Shots! - Oh my God.
- 喔!
- Ooh! - (SHRIEKS)
如果你們今晚不盡興,你們會後悔一輩子.
If you guys don't get lucky tonight, it's never going to happen.
我來擔任裁判 你想要加入嗎
I'm fielding offers. You want in?
- 待會見.
- (LAUGHING) - See me after.
(ELECTRONIC DANCE MUSIC PLAYS)
- 乾杯, 夥計們! - 呼!
- Cheers, guys! - Whoo!
太好了!
Yeah!
艾登, 也許我們該結賬了.
Adam, maybe we shouid ciose out the tab.
別擔心.
Hey, don't worry about it, man, don't worry about it.
我們能再來一杯伏特加嗎?
Hey, can we get another bottle of Ciroc?
- 跟我跳! - 不,不,不.
- Twirl me! - No, no, no.
來吧!
Come on!
($ ZEDD FEAT. MIRIAM BRYANT: "PUSH PLAY")
夥計,你去哪兒
Hey, buddy, where you going?
可能是一見鍾情.
Could be love.
(SONG CONTINUING)
(SONG ENDS)
起來吧
WOMAN: Wake up.
醒醒
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Hey, wake up.
我得走了
- Hmm? - I have to go.
你也該走了
So do you.
沒早餐嗎？
No breakfast?
我做錯什麼了嗎？
ADAM: Did I, uh, do something wrong?
要是你做錯了事,你不可能還在這兒了.
If you had done something wrong, you wouldn't be here, would you?
那麼...
(MUMBLES)
So...
那麼, 我們...
So, uh, we...
...走吧.
...are leaving.
等一下, 我都不知道你叫什麼.
Wait a second, I don't even know your name.
你是要走安全出口嗎?
Are you taking the fire escape?
好吧.
OK.
- 謝謝. - 不客氣.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
紅茶, 要加糖和奶油嗎？
Hey. Black, or cream and sugar?
- 你在跟蹤我? - 我只是想問問你叫什麼.
- You stalking me now? - I just want to know your name.
然後你可以和我交友,性愛, 要我的電話?
Why? So you can poke me, friend me, ask for my number?
是的,給一個聯繫方式吧.
Or you could just give me your number.
你不是我談對象的菜
You're not relationship material.
談對象？你想要談對象？
Relationship? You're looking for a relationship?
我愛談對象  我很在行
I love relationships. I'm great at relationships.
不.實際上我只想趕緊甩掉你.
No. Actually, I'm just trying to get rid of you nicely.
我們那個了嗎?
Didn't we have sex?
在我喝醉的時候喜歡鄉巴佬
I have a thing for bridge-and-tunnel guys when I drink.
你叫我鄉巴佬？
Did you just call me bridge-and-tunnel?
你帶我去吃芝士薯條.
You took me out for cheese fries.
乳酪薯條!
Cheese fries! (CHUCKLES)
然後呢?
Oh. Then what?
然後你就有了一夜情.
Then you had the night of your life.
你說的,不是我說的.
Your words, not mine.
喔... 紅茶.
Oh... Black.
艾登.? 我的名字是邁爾斯米徹姆.
MAN: Adam Cassidy? My name is Miles Meachum.
懷亞特先生想和你聊聊.
Mr. Wyatt would like to speak with you.
你怎麼知道我在哪兒?
ADAM: How did you know where I was?
我想我都不住在這兒.
I mean, I don't even live around here.
艾登先生.
Ah! Mr. Cassidy.
聲稱比我還瞭解我的生意的人.
The man who claims he knows my business better than I do.
坐吧.
Here, take a seat.
- 來杯酒? - 不,謝謝.
- Drop of vino? - Uh... No.
看起來你是我們一個會計漏洞的受益者.
It seems you were the beneficiary of an accounting error we made.
我不知道你在說什麼.
I don't know what you're taiking about.
Ethion自由基金.
The Ethion discretionary fund.
我的錢在哪兒?
Where's my money?
我們用於市場研究.
We used it on market research.
在RISE夜總會?
At Ciub Rise?
1萬6千美元?
Sixteen grand?
這一定會有一個詳盡的報告.
It must be a very detailed report.
你認為你能宰我,僥倖成功
You think you can rip me off and get away with it?
信用卡詐騙
Credit card fraud?
不,對不起,我會還回來的.
No, sir, I'm sorry. I'm gonna pay you back.
不,不行,這不是債務.
No you won't. It wasn't a loan.
現在有兩條路.
Now there's two ways we can piay this.
你願意做馬還是狗?
Are you a horse or a dog?
一匹馬是出於恐懼.他從鞭飛奔.
A horse is motivated by fear. He's running from the whip.
鞭子就是信用卡詐騙
The whip here being felony fraud.
- 他是狗. - 狗被饑餓驅使.
- He's a dog. - A dog is motivated by hunger.
他追蹤兔子,他的下一頓美食.
He's chasing the rabbit, his next meal.
你在布魯克林低收入家庭長大.
WOMAN: You were raised in a low-income home in Brooklyn.
你七歲的時候媽媽死了.
Your mother died when you were seven.
你的納稅顯示你還要負擔父親的生活.
Your W-2 says you now support your father.
所以?
So?
所以,這意味著你每天都要經過這座橋
So, it means you came across that bridge every day
急切的渴望成功.
hungry to succeed.
- 每個人都想成功. - 但不像我們這樣.
- Everyone wants to succeed. - Yeah, but not like us.
你父親做了 32 年警衛
Your father spent 32 years as a security guard.
- 你在說什麼? - 這到底在幹嘛?
- Where's the ambition in that? - What's this about?
你渴望擁有更多!
You want more out of life!
我和你一樣的長大. 不同的街區.
I grew up like you. I mean, different streets.
相同的夢, 但沒人給我,沒有人.
Same dream, but nobody gave it to me. No one.
如果我告訴你我能讓你發財 ?
And what if I toid you I could make you rich?
讓你的朋友重新獲得工作?
And give your friends theirjobs back?
你昨天展示的是一個聰明的創意,.
That was a smart pitch you gave yesterday.
我起步於Eikon公司.
I started out at Eikon.
喬克·哥達德是我的導師.
Jock Goddard was my mentor.
你認識他嗎
Do you know him?
是的,我知道
Yeah, of course I know him.
我的畢業論文研究半導體記憶體.
I did my graduate thesis on semi-conductor memory.
哥達德的基本要求手機並不是磚塊大小.
Goddard's basically the reason cell phones aren't the size of bricks.
他建立了Eikon.
He founded Eikon.
並最終成功上市
WOMAN: And built it into the largest publicly traded
成為全世界最大的科技公司
technology company in the world.
自從我離開他
And ever since I ieft, he has spent
想盡辦法試圖毀了我.
every waking moment trying to destroy me.
Eikon正在研發一種能夠改變遊戲格局的新的智慧手機.
Eikon has a new smartphone coming that's said to be a game-changer.
他們稱之為Occura.
They're calling it Occura.
你要去為Eikon工作.
You are going to work for Eikon.
- 什麼? - 幫我們得到我們想要的 你可以得到五十萬.
- What? - Get us in the door, you get 500K.
我們得到我們想要的 你會得到現有一百萬的優先認股權
Get us what we need, you'll see another million in stock options.
那個數目 可以讓你照顧父親, 當然遠勝於此.
Money like that
wouid aiiow you to take care of your father and a whole lot more.
Eikon不會聘用我的.
Eikon's notjust going to hire me.
他們會的,我們已經安排好了.
They will when we're done with you.
這是違法的. 這是在竊取商業機密.
This is illegal. It's stealing trade secrets.
這是你一直在等待的機會.
This is the opportunity you have been waiting for.
現在,你可以用昨晚的信用卡幹更多想幹的事了.
Now, you could have done a lot of things with that credit card iast night.
你父親的醫療保險費,你的畢業貸款,
Your father's health insurance premium, graduate school loans,
但你要城裏你的好友那兒搬出來,住到一個大房子裏
but you decided to take your mates out on the town, living it large.
因為你需要知道另一半人是怎麼生活的.
Because you want to know how the other half lives.
我們就是那另一半,富人!
We are the other half!
這是我要提供給你的條件.
That's what I'm offering you.
如果我拒絕呢?
If I say no?
你和你的朋友將受到法律最大程度的追究.
You and your friends will be prosecuted to the full extent of the law.
你不想只是坐著看我如何沏茶,對吧?
And you don't want to sit around and watch me make tea, do you?
(SIGHS)
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(TURNS OFF TV)
你是誰, 電視員警嗎?
What are you, the TV police?
- 你在睡覺. - 我只是眼睛閉起來了.
- You were asleep. - My eyes were closed.
去哪?
Where you going?
- 公司放假. - 休假, 什麼樣的假期?
- I caught a break at the company. - A break, what kind of break?
帶薪假.
A kind of break that pays our rent and keeps your pretty nurse around.
是個培訓, 我這個週末都不會回來.
It's a training thing, so I'll be gone all weekend.
週五晚上我們可以去本齊奧吃披薩,喝酒.
It's Friday night. I thought we were going to Benzio's for pizza and beer.
我要去工作了. 爸爸
I got to work, Dad. That's how you climb the ladder in this business.
你比手下工作辛苦多了.
You work harder than the guy below you.
這就是為什麼你一輩子待在原地做著相同的工作的原因.
Otherwise you get stuck doing the same job your whole life.
瞧...
Look... (SIGHS)
這兒有些錢. 你自己點餐, 好嗎?
Here's some money. You can order in, OK?
不.謝謝
No, no. Thanks.
好吧
Aii right.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
你為公司做些什麼, 茱蒂絲?
What exactly do you do for the company, Judith?
我有一個行為心理學博士學位
I have a PhD in behavioral psychology.
我可以幫你看看你為啥沒能成功.
I can take one look at you and tell you why you haven't succeeded.
你為啥不告訴我你真實的想法?
Why don't you tell me how you really feel?
我可以給你工具去提升
I can give you the tools to ascend
爬上美國公司的最高層.
to the highest ranks of corporate America.
但是你要改變你的態度.
But you have to lose the attitude.
這邊.
MAN: This way.
我帶你到房間去.
I'll show you to your room.
(GUNSHOT ECHOES)
當我們認識某人的時候 最直接的印象就形成了
When we meet someone, an immediate cognitive process takes place.
我們通常以貌取人.
We construct our first ideas on them based on their appearance.
所以你要想被接受,你必須看上去跟他們一樣.
So, if you want to be accepted, you have to look the part.
你必須去適應,融入.
You have to fit in to get in.
懷亞特和哥達德間發生了什麼事?
What happened with Wyatt and Goddard?
喬克·哥達德是個聰明的商人
Jock's a brilliant businessman.
他總是能在他的產品裏灌注很多他的神奇的理念,
He was always able to imbue his products with a magic of big ideas,
但懷亞特是大腦.
but Wyatt was the brains.
沒有他的設計,無一能成功面世.
Without his designs, none of it would have been possible.
聽起來像是完美的搭配.
Hmm. Sounds like a perfect pairing.
對哥達德, 算是. 懷亞特獻出了一生中最好的時光
For Goddard, yes. Wyatt gave him the best years of his life.
喬克·哥達德失去了兒子迪倫,因為那小子服藥過量
Jock lost his son Dylan to a drug overdose.
所以,如果你談到失去母親...
So, if you talk about losing your mother...
不, 別說了.
No, I won't.
他的上訴無效. 說你沒有父親.
Then, appeal to his void. Say you had no father figure.
我有父親.
I have a father.
你不想成為像他一樣的人.
You don't aspire to be like him.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
什麼能使我們信任.
JUDITH: Which brings us to trust.
如果你能使他信服,你也會像他
If you can convince him that you're just like him,
你和他分享一樣的信念,
that you share the same beliefs as him,
它會產生信任.
it will engender trust.
信任是間諜的前世今生.
And trust is the holy grail of espionage.
- 她讓這些聽起來很簡單.
- She makes it sound so easy. - (JUDITH CHUCKLES)
他看起來值得信賴
But this is a man who recognized me for who I was years before I did.
他跟我保持親密卻做出對敵人才會做的事.
He kept me close because that's what you do with an enemy.
當我不安,他答應跟我合作.
When I got restless, he promised me partnership. It was genius.
當我把我每一個想到的主意都給了他時我們的友誼也到了終點...
I saw the finish line and I gave him every good idea I ha...
- 這是誰? - 他是個新設計師.
- Who's this? - He's the new tailor.
喬治 蓋得勒, 先生.
I'm George Gardelo, sir.
我們單獨聊會好嗎,喬治?
Would you excuse us, George?
- 當然. - 只要一會兒.
- Yes. Of course. - Just for a second.
怎麼了?
What's going on?
這就是事情的原委.
NICOLAS: That's how it happens.
一個小傢伙用針和線擊敗了一個帝國.
A iittie guy with a needie and thread brings down an empire.
你真的相信?
You really believe that?
瞧,沒關係,你如果毫無破綻,你也不會被打垮.
Look, it doesn't matter. If you let no one in, you get burned by no one.
你知道畢卡索怎麼說的嗎?
You know what Picasso said?
"能工摹其形,巧匠攝其魂."
"A good artist copies. A great artist steais."
世界上沒有什麼東西是原創的,艾登.
There's nothing original left in the world, Adam.
我們都是在竊取別人的東西.
We're all stealing from someone.
你應該牢記這一點.
You might want to remember that.
如果我損失1%的市場,
NICOLAS: If I lose one percent market share,
我就毀了.
one percent, and I'm ruined.
那是荷蘭人的交易,
There is the Dutch deal,
但他們只能付給你Eikon'所給的一半的價錢.
but they're offering half ofwhat Eikon's willing to pay you.
不,我不介意.
No, no, I don't care.
我還是會考慮荷蘭人
I would rather counter the Dutch for a fraction
而不是哥達德.
than sell to Goddard.
什麼都比賣給Eikon好.
Anything's better than Eikon.
我知道.
JUDITH: I know.
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
你好
Hello?
什麼時候能幫我的朋友找到工作?
When are you going to find my friends jobs?
只要你給我們想要的.
As soon as you get me what I need.
你只有一次機會.
You only have one shot at this.
或許
Mate.
湯姆 寧格是Eikon公司執行人事協調員.
JUDITH: Tom Lungren is executive hiring coordinator for Eikon.
你的任務是取得聯繫.
Your objective here is to connect.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS IN BACKGROUND)
艾登?
Adam?
- 湯姆. - 湯姆 寧格.
- Tom. - Tom Lungren.
很高興見到你. 這位是艾瑪·詹寧斯,
Nice to meet you. Let me introduce Emma Jennings,
我們市場部門的頭兒.
head of our marketing department.
很高興見到你, 艾瑪.
Nice to meet you, Emma.
請坐
Please, sit down.
我們開始吧
Well, let me start off by saying that we're
從Ethion 3.0上面感興趣的部分說起吧.
huge fans of the work you did on Ethion 3.0.
你知道 這個產品目前還沒投入市場.
Well, you know, it hasn't been released yet, so.
是因為電源管理部分還沒有實現嗎?
Is that because power management doesn't deliver?
不,電源管理沒問題.
No, the power management is fine.
我們聽說的可不一樣.
That's not what we've heard.
我們正在調試網路模組
We're tweaking the networking module to make
以達到市場上最快的下載速度.
download speed the fastest on the market.
上帝,希望這不是我們找他的原因.
Oh, God. I hope that's not why we agreed to meet with him.
你能說說規格嗎?
Can you talk specs?
Orion 系統採用LTE Advanced(真正的4G),最大 44.2 mbps.
The Orion was an LTE Advanced with max speeds of 44.2 mbps.
我們的新平臺是 WAVE OS 7.5...
Our new platform is a WAVE OS 7.5...
它可能沒有解決7.0版本中的致命缺陷.
Which probably won't solve the biggest issues you had with 7.0.
- 它的銷量是你的兩倍 - 市場才是上帝.
- It outsold your model two to one. - Yeah, the marketing was genius.
我策劃的活動.
I spearheaded that campaign.
然後,你知道你善於隱藏缺陷.
Then you know you're good at hiding flaws.
你們見過面嗎?
Have you two met?
沒有
No.
絕對沒有
我覺得我們一開始就弄錯了.
I think we got off on the wrong foot.
總是做好自己的功課,這是你說的,對吧
Aiways do your homework. That's what you said, isn't it?
下次堅持自己的意見
Next time follow your own advice.
- 不是 湯姆 寧格?不僅僅只有湯姆 寧格
- It wasn't Tom Lungren? - It wasn'tjust Tom Lungren.
我告訴你他可能還會找其他人
I told you he might bring someone else.
我認識嗎?
Someone that I knew?
發生什麼事了
What happened?
我力挽狂瀾, 四處聯絡, 報了一個價, 坑人的天價.
I saved the day. Connected. Pulled an offer, a big-ass offer.
讓我們帶你去新公寓吧.
(CHUCKLES) Let's take you to your new apartment.
- 什麼公寓? - 到時候你就知道了.
- What apartment? - You'll see.
哇哦.
Whoa.
希望你會喜歡.
Thought you'd like it.
這是我的？
This is mine?
當然.
JUDITH: (CHUCKLES) Of course.
Eikon的新總經理看上去要像個有錢人.
Eikon's newest executive needs to look the part.
(CHUCKLES)
很高興再見到你, 艾登.
It's nice to see you again, Adam.
按照我們的約定, 我們已將五十萬元打入了仲介帳戶.
Per our agreement, we've deposited $500,000 into an escrow account.
我們收到消息 哥達德未來的兩個月可能會在奧羅拉
JUDITH: We're hearing Goddard could debut Aurora in the next two months,
我下載了所有你的工作夥伴的背景資料.
so I've downloaded background files on all your co-workers.
首先, 艾瑪·詹寧斯.
First, Emma Jennings.
父親是喬治·詹寧斯,
Father, George Jennings, was
紐約長老會的外科主任.
Chief of Surgery at New York Presbyterian.
和四個兄弟一起長大,
She grew up with four brothers,
總是在男孩俱樂部的外面徘徊.
was aiways on the outside of the boys club, looking in.
拼命地想在男人主宰額世界中獲得成功.
Desperately wants to succeed in a man's world,
所以她總是整個公司裏準備最充分的人.
so she's always the most prepared person in the room.
在幾個小時之前的話這些資訊很有用
Would have been useful a couple of hours ago.
不要浪費你的時間.她有一定的標準.
Don't waste your time. She has certain standards.
茱蒂絲, 或許你並不像你自己想像的那麼聰明.
Judith, maybe you're not as smart as you think you are.
現在不要總是說你在想什麼,親愛的.
Now don't always say what you think, dariing.
因為從現在開始了,你不能袒露心聲.
Because from here on out, you are all the way under.
我們只能通過這部手機通信
We'll be communicating through this phone only.
你需要回復我的電話,無論什麼時間
You will respond to my calls, no matter the time, day or night.
- 你接吧.
- (PHONE CHIMES) - You got it.
早上好, 先生.
Good morning, sir.
我需要他體檢報告的複印件送到我的辦公室.
I want a copy of his body scan sent to my office.
好的,先生
Yes, sir.
- 艾登. - 寧格先生.
- Adam. - Mr. Lungren.
你別那樣叫我,讓我感覺自己很老
I told you. You gotta stop calling me that, you're gonna make me feel old.
- 歡迎來到Eikon. - 謝謝,這裏太棒了.
- Welcome to Eikon. - Thank you. It's great to be here.
- 我們很慶幸你能來 - 謝謝.
- We're damn glad to have you. - OK, good.
底層是禁地 人事部門,
The lower floors are Legal, HR,
中間層是其他部門,包括市場部.
middle floors are all the other departments, including marketing.
38樓研發中心,最高安全機密.
The 38th floor is R&D, top security projects.
我們現在在40樓..
And we're here on the 40th.
在這樓裏和周圍有些注意事項.
There's just a few tricks to being in this building and getting around.
你鑰匙卡應用的指紋會生成條碼
Your thumbprint on a keycard app generates a bar code
你可以去任何允許你去的地方.
that gets you anywhere your clearance is allowed.
好的
Aii right.
那麼哥達德有什麼口號嗎?
So any words ofwisdom on Goddard?
能力與誠懇.
Be brilliant and be genuine.
他很有慧眼 這是你的辦公室.
He can spot a fraud a mile away. Here's your office.
那麼X型意味著社交關係網絡
So, Type X was meant for social networking,
但事實證明人們並不怎麼需要友誼
but it turns out that people don't always want their friends
準確的知道他們在哪里.
to know where they are so precisely.
沒錯.什麼是系統技術?
Right. What's the system tech?
就是3DPS, 就像 GPS,加上高精度三角測量.
It's 3DPS, which is like GPS plus precise triangulation.
我對那個很熟悉.
I'm familiar with it.
問題是,重量是以前的兩倍,電池消耗三倍.
Problem is, it's twice as heavy with three times the battery drain.
所以你把一個死題交給我了？
So, you're handing me a dead fish.
你只有72小時去完善然後展示給哥達德.
You've got 72 hours before you present to Goddard.
謝謝.
Thank you.
這是一個即時跟蹤裝置,可以用於新用途
It's a real-time tracking device that needs a new purpose.
這次展示很重要,你必須給他留下極深的印象
It's all about the presentation. You have to impress him.
我明白我該怎麼做
Yes, I understand what I have to do.
我會和研發中心的夥計們來一次頭腦風暴.
I'll schedule a brainstorming session with our best R&D guys.
你為啥幹這個工作, 茱蒂絲?
Why do you do this work, Judith?
是出於忠誠,還是為了錢?
I mean, is it out of loyalty, or is itjust money?
難道你還有足夠的時間思考?
Don't you have enough to think about?
伊娜,我需要你把大家召集起來開會
Rowena, I need you to put together
研發小組.
an R&D focus group.
我不管,叫醒他們.
I don't care, wake them up.
準備好通知我,再見.
Call me when everything's in place. Bye.
(TV PLAYS INDISTINCTLY)
士兵.
Soldiers.
士兵們需要時刻知道對方在哪里.
Soldiers need to know where each other are at aii times.
- 他們有GPS - 是的.
- They have GPS. - Yeah.
GPS 適合導航,但在室內毫無用途
GPS is great for navigation, but it doesn't work indoors.
不能確定你是在一樓還是在九樓,
Can't tell if you're on the first floor or the ninth,
所以在城市爭奪中毫無用途.
so it's useless in urban warfare.
但是3DPS,
But with 3DPS,
如果我能通過木馬跟蹤每個人的每一封電子郵件...
if I can Trojan-horse tracking data in an e-mail to each of them...
...我能讓它工作起來.
...I could make this thing work.
- 你打給誰? - 我自己的研發團隊.
- Who are you calling? - My own R&D focus group.
卡維, 是我,我需要你幫忙
Yo, Kev, it's me. I need your help.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYS INSIDE)
我被幾家公司招募了...
I got recruited by one of those...
...獵頭.
...headhunters.
長話短說,我現在給Eikon公司幹活.
Long story short, I work for Eikon now.
我聽說他們不招聘.
I heard they weren't hiring.
我可能很幸運吧,我猜
I got lucky, I guess. (CHUCKLES)
我想也是
I guess.
我正在忙一個專案
Well, hey, I've been working on what we talked about,
軍事上可能用的著
and the military thing is definitely possible.
我調試了一下Eikon的軟體.
I just tweaked the Eikon software a little.
我把這個叫做迴旋鏢
I'm calling it the Boomerang.
檢查一下吧.
Just check this out.
我把3DPS 資料郵件發給你,我還有艾利森.
I sent your 3DPS data e-mail to you, me and Allison.
現在我們的電話一起聯網了.
So now our phones track each other working in unison.
你是對的, 3DPS,那是完全不同的技術.
And you were right, the 3DPS, that's what makes the difference.
你找我找的太對了.
That was a good call, by the way.
夥計,太棒了,幹的好
Dude, that's awesome. You crushed this. Good job.
但那不是全部
KEVIN: Yeah, but that ain't all.
把艾利森接進來.
Pick up Allison.
你要點什麼?  - 一杯橙汁.
- ALLISON: What can I get you? - MAN: Another OJ.
你是怎麼做到的?
ALLISON: One more OJ.
How the hell did you do that?
誰點的橙汁?
ALLISON: Who orders orange juice in a bar?
有人想要保持他的神秘感.
MAN: Someone who wants to keep his edge. (CHUCKLES)
- 你叫什麼名字? - 艾利森.
- What's your name? - Allison.
(CHUCKLES)
你認識那個人嗎?
Do you know that guy?
嘿, 橙汁!
Hey, OJ!
她是我的馬子.
We're sleeping together, me and her.
很高興認識你, 艾利森.
Nice to meet you, Allison.
我就一直坐在這裏 看她和別人調情.
Aii I do is sit around here, watching her get hit on aii the time.
太他媽累了!
It's exhausting!
我想找份工作.
I need a job.
(TV PLAYS INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
早晨好,卡洛琳. 讓一下.
Good morning, Caroline. Excuse me.
- 喬克·哥達德. - 艾登.凱斯帝.
- Jock Goddard. - Adam Cassidy.
原來是你,一切還好吧,安頓的怎麼樣?
Of course you are. Everything all right? Settling in OK?
- 謝謝. - 辦公室如何?
- Yeah. Thank you. - How's your office?
- 很漂亮,謝謝. - 很好,我們開始吧
- Oh, yeah, it's beautiful. Thank you. - Good. Let's get started.
好的.
OK.
先生, 我看你已浪費了很多錢
Well, sir, I'm afraid you've wasted a lot of money
開發型號 X的社交網路設備.
developing Type X as a social networking device.
不過這個設備的軍方用途不可否認.
But the military applications of this device are undeniable.
早上我給大家發了封郵件
I sent you all an e-mail this morning
我把一份類似3DPS的資料發送去給你辨認.
in which I encoded 3DPS-like data to identify you.
除了我以外在座的每一位都收到了郵件.
Everyone I sent an e-mail to is in this room. Except for one.
誤傷死亡仍然存在是現在戰爭的一個悲殘現狀.
Death by friendly fire remains a sad reality ofwar.
3DPS 比 GPS更為精確,並且可在Z軸向工作.
3DPS is more precise than GPS and works on a Z-axis.
雖然對普通人來說這個產品太重,
While the product was deemed too heavy for civilians,
不過對於士兵增加 12 盎司不算什麼.
an added 12 ounces is nothing to a soldier.
所以你們應該能意識到我們的手機的前景了?
So this is all so you can see what fioor our phones are on?
是的,在激烈的戰爭中它會表現的與眾不同
Yes. 'Cause in the heat of battle that can be the difference
能殺死敵人保護自我...或者...誤殺自己人
between killing the enemy or...
...killing your own.
X手機可以挽救她的生命.
Type Xjust saved her life.
早.
Good morning.
早, 對不起.
Good morning, sorry.
你有多長時間可以和我們在一起?
Morning.
How long have you had with this?
72小時,先生.
ADAM: Seventy-two hours, sir.
讓我們為艾登組建一個團隊.
Let's put together a team for Adam.
設計,工程.讓我們看看能否獲得美國國防部的資助.
Design, engineering. Let's see ifwe can get some DOD funding.
困難? 不? 沒問題.
Issues? No? Good.
那最好.
Good.
- 棒極了. - 很好.
- Nice work. - OK.
我想一切進展順利.
I thought that went pretty well.
- 新手的好運氣.
- Beginner's luck. - (ADAM LAUGHS)
- 想取悅你還真不容易. - 非你所想.
- You are hard to please. - Not that you'd remember.
這週末我和你一起晚餐.
Let me take you to dinner this weekend.
這週末我必須去漢普頓.
I have to be in the Hamptons this weekend.
好吧. 我和你一起去.
Oh, good. I'll come with you.
這算是邀請嗎.
It wasn't an invitation.
好的.
OK.
嗨, 艾登. 我在喬克·哥達德辦公室給你來電.
(BEEPS)
WOMAN: Hi, Adam. I'm calling from Jock Goddard's office.
喬克邀請一些訪客去漢普頓的家裏
Jock is having a few people over to his house in the Hamptons
時間是星期六,他希望你也來.
on Saturday and he'd like you to join him.
(BEEPS)
現在我們去爭取軍事資助.
So now we go for military funding.
祝賀你,夥計
Dude, that's great. Congratulations, man.
嘿嘿,所以,我有一事相求.
Hey, so, I got a favor to ask.
我下周要到Eikon面試.
I got an interview at Eikon next week.
我不過是厚厚簡歷中一份子毫不出眾
And I know I'm gonna be another resume in a stack
除非我想點吸引人的點子
if I don't build some traction.
是的.
Right.
如此啟齒有些尷尬,不過...
So, I feel awkward even asking you this, but...
別擔心.
Hey, of course.
週一我會和人事打招呼的.
Aii right, I'll speak to HR on Monday.
放心吧.
Aii right.
謝謝.
Thanks.
(SUBWAY TRAIN RUMBLING, SCREECHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
這傢夥很出色.
Nicest guy.
闖過紅燈撞到了後面的車.
Right through the red light and hit the back of the car.
- 非常抱歉. - 有人迷路了.
- Very apologetic. - Somebody looks lost.
噢  嘿!
Oh, hey!
- 噢  . - 嗨.
- Hi. - Hey.
- 他在這兒. - 很高興你能來.
- There he is. - I'm glad you could make it.
- 謝謝你的邀請, 哥達德先生. - 叫我喬克.
- Thanks for having me, Mr. Goddard. - Jock.
- 你認識 湯姆,對吧. - 嗨.
- You know Tom, of course. - Hey.
喬克 和我說我的股票升值很多,因為你們 X型產品即將推出.
Jock tells me my stock's gone up in value since your Type X pitch.
第一擊就爆掉了計分牌.就該這麼幹
First time up at bat and you bang it off the scoreboard? Way to go.
這是 艾瑪.她負責我們新的Occura智慧型電話市場工作
And this is Emma. She's spearheading the marketing
on our new smartphone, Occura.
衣服真漂亮.
Nice suit.
看出來了嗎,她可是普林斯頓常青藤大學的高材生喲.
Watch our for her. She's one of those Ivy Leaguers. Princeton.
真的？
Yale, actually.
他的兄弟也上的那所學校.
Where her brothers went.
你怎麼知道我是耶魯的?
How did you know I went to Yale?
Facebook或是別的地方聽說的.
It was on Facebook or something.
喔.
Ah.
那麼多隱私哦.
So much for privacy.
隱私.笑話,沒這樣的事
Privacy. Absoiute myth, no such thing.
- 湯姆, 想喝一杯嗎? - 當然.
- Tom, you want a drink? - Yeah, absolutely.
一杯白蘭地, 先生?
MAN: A glass ofwine, sir?
- 是的. - 礦泉水, 加冰.
- White wine. - JOCK: Mineral water, cold.
待會見.
See you later.
(PHONE CHIMES)
有點像波爾多,太幹了.
Kind of like a Bordeaux, more dry.
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
如果你在找廁所,走過了.
If you're looking for the bathroom, you missed it.
是的, 不好意思, ...
Yeah, sorry, I, uh...
我看到那個收音機了. 還能工作嗎?
I saw the radio. Does it work?
是的.還能用,我做的.
Yeah, they work. They all work. I built them.
十多歲的時候的愛好.
That's how I spent my teens. Ham radio.
你在哪兒長大?
Where'd you grow up?
漢密爾頓, 3500多人的小鎮.
Town of Hamilton, 3500 people.
那是哪里?
Where is that?
不值一提.
It doesn't matter.
因為你讓我想起了懷亞特公司.我非常吃驚他們放你走
You remind me of Wyatt. I'm surprised he let you go.
他們對此不感興趣.
He wasn't too happy about it.
我知道有一天他們會成為強有力競爭對手.
I knew he'd be my competition someday.
在他們起步之前我就知道.
I knew it before he did.
那你為什們還要庇護他呢?
Why'd you take him under your wing?
不是因為他. 我們要開發出出色的產品
It's not about him. It's about putting products out there
讓人們生活的更好.
to make people's lives better.
競爭才會推動創新.
Competition fuels innovation.
否則, Eikon不會發展到今天.
Without it, Eikon wouldn't be where it is today.
這是哪里?
And where is that?
革命的前夜.
On the eve of a revolution.
那是你兒子嗎?
Is that your son?
是的,迪倫.
Yeah, that's Dylan.
一旦你有一點成功,你會開始思考
You have a bit of success, you begin to think
你已經可以控制一些事, 但是...
that you've got some control over things, but... (SCOFFS)
...很快倒楣的事就會發生.
...shit happens to everybody.
是啊.
Yeah.
我7歲時喪母.
I lost my mother when I was seven.
你還記得她嗎?
Do you remember her?
不太記得了.
Not much.
我感覺她逐漸離我遠去.
I feel like I lose her a little more every day.
我也是.
Yeah.
迪倫死後的很多夜晚,
Couple nights after Dilly died,
我常在夜晚驚醒.
I woke up in the middle of the night in a panic.
翻遍整個房子,他的整個房間...
Rummaged through the whole house, his whole room...
...試圖找到一點慰籍.
...looking for anything.
塗鴉畫, 作業本...
Kid's drawings, schoolwork...
...網球鞋.
...old pair of tennis shoes.
一切能回憶起他的東西.
Anything that wouid keep him aiive.
(SIGHS)
前廳, 在樓梯口.
The front hall, under the stairs.
先生?
Sir?
衛生間.
The bathroom.
謝謝.
Thanks.
(PHONE CHIMES)
你也知道,西裝其實不差啦.
EMMA: You know, the suit's not all that bad.
你不用藏著這裏.
You don't have to hide way out here.
我這是,呃,欲擒故縱.
I was, uh, playing hard to get.
但你已經得到了.
But you're already gotten.
告訴我,
So tell me,
你怎麼會瞭解我那麼多事
how is it that you know so much about me
而我卻對你一無所知?
and I know nothing about you?
嗯,我祖母有一小排房間.
It's this, uh, little row home my grandmother owned.
我們五個人共用洗手間.
Five of us sharing one bathroom.
我爸爸是警衛.
My dad was a security guard.
現在他有肺氣腫,但仍吸煙.
Now he has emphysema, but still smokes.
我敢肯定他把煙藏在護士那兒.
And I'm pretty sure he's putting it to the nurse I'm paying for.
當我想到要失去他...
When I think of losing him...
啊哈...
Aah...
你呢?
What about you?
我來自一個良好家族...
I come from a family where...
家裏期望太高了,我真的難以達成.
...the expectation is so high that I can't really ever succeed.
也好,我一直還在努力
It's fine, it's just that I keep trying.
因此...
So...
我想休息了.
I'm trying to sleep my way to the top.
一起嗎?
Are we covered?
(CHUCKLES)
帶我回家吧?
Come on. Take me home?
好吧.
Yeah.
($ LISSIE: "1 ,2")
(SONG ENDS)
(FAUCET SQUEAKS, WATER PATTERING)
(TV PLAYING INDISTINCTLY)
爸爸?
Dad?
來了個客人.
You got a visitor.
誰?
Who are you?
你或許可以把電池拆掉.
You might want to remove the battery from your cellular device.
什麼?
What?
你認為因為你不接電話,他們就找不到你?
You think 'cause you're not on a call, they can't hear you?
探員甘布.
Agent Gambie.
我是FBI的犯罪調查部門.
I'm with the FBI's Criminal Investigation Division.
我們在懷亞特公司調查了五年了.
We've been looking at the Wyatt Corp for about five years now.
- 我不在懷亞特工作. - 約翰·摩爾做的.
- I don't work for Wyatt. - John Moore did.
他09年就參與了懷亞特的培訓計畫
He was in Wyatt's training program in '09.
史黛拉·羅斯, 像你一樣從懷亞特跳到Eikon.
Stella Ross, migrated from Wyatt to Eikon like you.
兩個月後,她汽車的轉向柱爆炸.
Two months later, her steering column exploded.
理查·麥卡利斯特...
And Richard McAiiister...
...那個 Ethion任命你起草關閉的.
...whose Ethion work you drafted off of.
我沒有終止他的工作.
I didn't draft off his work.
一個月前,你還在懷亞特閒晃.
A month ago, you were circling the drain at Wyatt.
現在你卻是Eikon的座上賓? 別騙我.
Now you're some hotshot exec over at Eikon? Don't bullshit me.
好的, 我想你可以走了.
OK, I think it's time for you to go.
你以為懷亞特會給你一大筆錢然後讓你安然離開
You think Wyatt's gonna fill your pockets and let you walk?
我不知道你在說什麼?
I don't know what you're talking about, OK?
別這樣,艾登.
Come on, Adam.
你以為你能瞞多久?
How long do you think you can keep this up?
所有這一切只要一個錯誤,一個失誤就會敗露.
Aii it takes is one mistake, one slip up.
對不起,我幫不了你.
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
別後悔莫及.
Just don't wait till it's too late.
(SIGHS)
(CHILDREN SHOUTING PLAYFULLY)
你想要告訴我發生什麼事了嗎?
You wanna tell me what's going on?
你不會理解的.
You wouldn't understand.
是的,我太忙了
Yeah, I was probably too busy
每天三餐放在你面前
putting three meals in front of you every day
給你所有的親人的疼愛.
and giving you all the love that parents had.
來吧,艾登,我們會有一個完美的生活.
Come on, Adam. We had a perfect life.
你知道,如果你的保險能支付一半...
You know, if your insurance covered even half ofwhat mom needed...
不用和病魔糾纏,你希望我做什麼?
Don't try to revise death. What did you want me to do?
我希望你奮鬥.
I wanted you to fight.
我想我們至少能給媽媽一次機會.
I wanted us to have enough to at least give her a chance.
但你卻放棄了.
You gotta give that up.
這些公司偷走了這麼多,沒什麼可賺了.
These companies steal so much, there's nothing left to earn.
但你也沒做什麼來改變.
Yeah, what you're doing doesn't make it right.
不.
No.
沒人能改變.
No one can make it right.
既然如此,我為什麼不能得到屬於自己的一份?
So, why shouldn't I get my share? Huh?
FBI剛離開.
The FBI just walked out of our house.
我不想跟你一樣.
I don't want to end up like you.
這就是他掛了的原因.
So that's what he's up to.
這是你自己找的.
That's what you wanted.
我現在不想了. 這不是我.
I'm done now. This isn't who I am.
就是你,你搜過他?
This is exactly who you are. Did you frisk him?
你藏了一些東西?
You hiding something?
住手!
Knock it off! (GROANING)
你最近有點喜怒無常?
You've been a little temperamental lately, haven't you?
你喜歡上那女孩了?
Are you faiiing for that giri?
- 他愛上 喬克了. - 好吧,好吧!
- He's falling for Jock. - ADAM: All right, all right!
他說什麼?
What'd he talk about?
他談到了研發進展,以及產品豐富了人們的生活.
He talked about progress, enriching people's lives.
他談他的兒子了嗎?
Yeah, he talk about his son?
說了一點.
Yeah. A little.
好像排練好的?
It seem rehearsed?
不.
No.
第一次就說了.
It did the first time he told it.
是當喬克·哥達德春風得意的時候,
That was when the world fell in love with Jock Goddard,
悲傷的父親.
the grieving father.
死亡兒子的故事救了Eikon.
That story of his little dead boy saved Eikon.
我給你你想要的, 對吧?
I got what you asked for, OK?
我們有約定.我只想拿到我的錢.
We had a deal. I just want my money.
喔, 他想拿錢.
Oh, he wants his money.
我們會幫你保管的.等你完成任務再說.
We'll keep your money for you. You'll be doing five to ten upstate.
我得到參數,這是我們的預定.
I got the specs. That was the deal.
圖片還不夠.
Pictures are no good to me.
我想知道它怎麼工作的,我想拿到手研究!
I need to know what it does, I need to hold it in my hand and see it run!
明白嗎,把全部交給我!
Do you understand me? Put it in my fucking hand!
然後呢? 我像理查一樣的消失?
Or what? I end up like Richard?
喬克建了個模型.
Jock builds one prototype.
一切都是秘密進行的,需要等到BETA版本.
It's assembled in the vault, piece by piece, until beta trials.
所以資料都封在38樓.
It stays in the vault on the 38th floor.
沒有檔案,沒有源碼,你什麼也做不了
Without files, without source code, you can't do...
不,我不需要檔案.
No, I don't need his files.
我只需要看到他的願景.
I just need to see his vision.
不,我不幹了,我退出.
No, I'm not doing this anymore. I'm out.
(SCOFFS)
你退出?我說你退出的時候你才能退出,我的孩子
You're out? You are only out, my son,
when I say you're out!
由不得你了.
I own you right now.
明白嗎?我可以決定一切..
You see? I can get to anyone.
(GRUNTING)
別太為難自己了.
Don't make this harder than it has to be.
這只不過是生意, 艾登. 每個人都偷, 每個人都在說謊.
It's just business, Adam. Everybody steals, everybody lies.
這裏沒有對和錯.
There's no right or wrong.
只有輸和贏.
There's just winning or losing.
現在優先任務是提取艾瑪的指紋.
NICOLAS: Now the first order of business is lifting Emma's fingerprints.
我的父母都會在
So my parents are having this thing
週末參加哥哥的婚禮.
for my brother's engagement this weekend.
你想和我一起去嗎?
You wanna go with me?
見你的父母?
To meet your parents?
只是共進晚餐.
It's just dinner and drinks.
你們, 喔...
You, uh...
你不是說我只是為了床上關係嗎?
You sure I'm relationship material?
你知道啥? 只是... 只是會覺得無聊而已.
You know what? It's... It's actually gonna be really boring.
- 你不去也好. - 嘿.
- Probably better if you don't. - Hey.
我當然會去.
Of course I will.
無聊也去?
Even if it is boring?
是的,無所謂了.
Yeah, even if it's boring.
(EMMA LAUGHS)
怎麼了你?
KEVIN: Hey, what happened to you?
卡維,你在幹嘛?
Kev! What are you doing here?
你以為我在做啥?
What do you think I'm doing here?
面試啊.
Your interview. Right.
忘了...
Uh...
- 怎麼樣? 我和人事部門說了. - 不,你沒有.
- How'd it go? I spoke to HR. - No, you didn't.
對不起, 兄弟. 我, 忘了...
I'm sorry, man. I, uh...
我最近壓力很大,完全忘了.
I've been under a ton of pressure. I completely forgot...
是啊, 我懂, 你去了新公司,買了新車,有了新女朋友
Yeah, I understand, man. Your new apartment, new car, new girlfriend.
你根本不瞭解我的處境.
You have no idea what I'm deaiing with.
是的我不瞭解.我大概從未瞭解過.
No, I don't. And I don't think I ever wiii.
- 謝謝. - 別走, 卡維. 我真的很抱歉.
- Thanks. - Come on, Kev. I'm sorry, man.
卡維!
Kev!
哥達德先生想見你.
Mr. Goddard wants to see you.
阿哈.好的,我知道了
Uh-huh. Yeah, I understand that.
懷亞特不得不考慮我們的提議.他沒的選
Wyatt has to consider our offer. He has no choice.
我的意思是,他此刻像是在泰坦尼克號上跳踢踏舞.
I mean, he's tap dancing on the Titanic.
進來吧.
Come on in.
瞧,誰來了.
Look, somebody just walked in.
我得到一些東西,不得不處理
I've got something I've got to deal with.
好的. 謝謝.
Aii right. Thanks.
別忘了你在酒吧有留座.
WOMAN: Don't forget, you have a lunch reservation at the club.
我們去兜兜風,一起吃午飯.
Come on. Let's take a drive. I'll buy you lunch.
今天早上收到關於你的一些有趣的資料.
Got some interesting news this morning concerning you.
在和你聊之前我想確認一下真假.
Thought I'd make sure it was true before I talk to you about it.
- 一切還好吧? - 你說呢.
- Is everything all right? - You tell me.
國防部給 X型機注資了.
The DOD has given us preliminary funding for Type X.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
- 我們要走了, 哥達德先生. - 謝謝, 夥計.
- We'll leave it here, Mr. Goddard. - Thanks, Bud.
- 你怎麼看? - 太強大了.
- Well, what do you think? - It's powerful.
是啊.
Yeah, it is.
X型機需要提前還貸以節省開支
Consider it a loaner for saving Type X.
- 喬克, 我不能接受. - 你可以的.
- Jock, I couldn't. - Yeah, you could.
喝了這果汁,補充點能量.
Power is the juice, get used to drinking it.
我聽到你聊Occura.
I heard you talking about Occura.
外面有很多瘋傳.
There's a lot of buzz about it.
是的Occura正在開發
Yeah, Occura's been, uh, gestating
好多年了.
for... quite a few years.
直到最近我們才能
We only recently were able to put
組裝所有部件,使之成型.
all of the elements together to make it happen.
- 一杯咖啡. - 一杯水.
- I'll have coffee. - I'll have a water.
很好.
Very good.
想像一下散步時除了手機啥都不帶.
Imagine walking around with nothing but your ceii phone.
沒有錢包,沒有鑰匙.
No wallet, no keys.
手機像一個數字錢包.
Like a digital wallet.
像駕駛執照,像信用卡,
It'll be your driver's license, it'll be your credit card,
像很多其他的東西.
it'll be more than that.
超薄. 可折疊, 能自己充電
Super slim. Foldable, with a battery that recharges itself
from any ambient electrical source.
它知道你在哪里,和誰在一起.
It'll know where you've been, who you've been with.
它會幫你安排日程,管理支出,
It'll track your priorities, expenditures,
照看身體, 提供日程表.
your health, calendar.
知道你是誰,幾乎可以成為你的全部.
It will know who you are. And it's aii ours.
你真的以為同一屋簷下的人們會想要獲取這樣的私人資訊
You think people really want all that personal information
這和熟人無關, .
under one roof?
It's not the roof that matters, Adam.
這是一種在家的溫暖感覺.
It's the warm fuzzy feeling of the home under it.
現在的人們都有些精神分裂了,不知道自己是誰
People are so distracted these days, they don't know who they are.
但我們瞭解.
But we will.
我們甚至比他們自己更瞭解自身.
We'll know them better than they know themselves.
喔, 天啊.
Oh, my goodness.
喬克.
Jock.
尼克.
Nick.
多久沒見了?
How long has it been?
沒多久吧.
Not long enough.
你一點沒變.
You look like you're holding up all right.
喔, 我還好,那陣風把你吹到這兒來的?
Oh, I'm doing fine. What brings you here?
我來吃午飯.
Lunch. Lunch brings me here.
- 你還記得茱蒂絲嗎. - 喔, 當然.
- You remember Judith. - Oh, of course.
- 你好, 茱蒂絲? - 還行.
- How are you, Judith? - Good.
你記得 艾登.凱斯帝嗎. 他設計了 Ethion.
You remember Adam Cassidy. He designed your Ethion.
當然
Yes, he did.
你好,艾登
Hello, again, Adam.
他讓我想起了你.
He reminds me of you.
遙想當年,你拋棄了我們
Way back when, before you walked out on us.
我們不要顛倒事實吧.
Let's not muddle the facts.
你要我走,然後把門關上了.
You asked me to walk and locked the door behind me.
不過,我比艾登聰明.
Besides, I was smarter than Adam here.
我沒有浪費時間拍你的馬屁.
And I didn't spend aii my time kissing your ass.
(CHUCKLES)
Ethion項目進展如何? 我們早有耳聞.
How is Ethion? We've heard remarkably little about it.
嗯. Ethion進展順利. Occura專案如何?
Mm. Ethion's fine. How's Occura?
一切正常.
Right on schedule.
相信你永遠無法複製.
And it's something you're never going to be able to duplicate.
真的?
Is that so?
尼克,沒忘了我們曾經共用創意 ?
Remember when we used to share ideas, Nick?
我沒忘.
I try not to.
只要我們一碰頭,沒什麼解決不了的事.
When we put our heads together, there was no problem we couldn't solve.
沒什麼做不出來的東西.
Nothing we couldn't make.
應該是沒什麼我解決不了的困難.
There was no problem I couldn't solve.
沒什麼我做不出來的東西.
Nothing I couldn't make.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
我懷念你的友誼.
JOCK: I miss your friendship.
為什麼我們不再坐下來談談呢.
Why don't we sit down together sometime.
(CHUCKLES)
總說放屁的話. 你坐著就像...
Aiways so fuii of shit. You sit here like...
...像個什麼了不起大人物,
...like some big shot with boy wonder here,
去你的吧,搞得好像我們真的還有關係似的.
blowing smoke up your ass like it's still relevant.
事實是我都想埋了你,
The truth is, I'm gonna bury you,
你的人現在為我工作.
and your boy here is gonna be working for me again.
因為為你工作就意味著為我工作.
Because working for you, means he'll be working for me.
(CHUCKLING)
別讓午餐變冷了, 尼克.
Don't let your lunch get cold, Nick.
很高興見到你, 茱蒂絲.
Nice seeing you, Judith.
他正在找哥達德.
MEACHUM: He's running search after search on Goddard.
找什麼?
What is he looking for?
我不知道.
JUDITH: I don't know.
我認為我們這個男孩已經開始軟弱了
I think this boy's gone soft on us.
(PHONE CHIMING)
(SIGHS)
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
你忘了我的電話?
MEACHUM: Were you going to ignore my call?
你應該告訴我懷亞特會去.
You should have told me Wyatt was gonna be there.
你怎麼跟的這麼緊,看上去很緊張.
Why do you keep pacing so much? You look nervous.
你有什麼要告訴我嗎?
You have something you want to tell me?
你在哪?
Where are you?
現在我來說明下一步怎麼辦.
Now let me explain to you how this is going to work.
我們先幹掉你的一個朋友.
We hit one of your friends first.
或許是個女孩.
Or maybe the girl.
如果你敢動她...
If you even touch her...
那麼去拿到我們要的.
Then get us what we need.
(SHOUTS, GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(STATIC CRACKLES)
你有兩天時間去入侵Eikon的秘密.
You have two days to break into Eikon.
這是最後一次警告.
This is your last warning.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(ENGINE RACING)
幫幫我!快來幫幫我
Help! Help me! Somebody help me!
他說我有兩天時間
He said I had two days. That was the night before last.
這些人無處不在.將相機佈滿在你房子周圍
These people are everywhere. Put cameras in your house.
對不起. 我只是...
I'm sorry. I just...
我都糊塗了, 爸爸.
I messed up, Dad.
我想我知道自己在做什麼.
I thought I knew what I was doing.
(GIRL'S LAUGHTER ECHOES)
你必須找到辦法.
FATHER (ECHOING): You have to figure a way out.
艾登.
Adam.
- 艾登! - 很嚴重, 知道嗎?
- Adam! - This is serious, OK?
你必須想辦法.
You got to figure a way out.
沒那麼容易.
It's not that easy.
懂嗎? 我讓那麼多關心我的人都處於危險之中.
OK? I put a lot of people I care about in danger.
艾登, 我覺得應該向FBI自首.
Adam, I think the FBI is the only option.
那樣會坐牢的.
I could go to jail.
否則他們會殺了你.
Or they could kill you.
(TV PLAYS INDISTINCTLY)
(PHONE CHIMING)
有一輛黑色的車突然竄出來撞到了他
ALLISON: There was a black car and it just came out of nowhere and it hit him.
慢一點. 他還好嗎? 你在哪兒?
Slow down. Is he all right? Where are you?
一整天我都在找你. 卡維在醫院,他還好.
I've been trting to reach you all day. Kev's at the hospital, but he's OK.
他們在催我們出院.
I think they're discharging us now.
有目擊證人嗎? 有誰找到線索嗎?
OK, were there witnesses? Did anyone get the plates?
我不知道,一切發生的都太快了.
I don't think so. I don't know, itjust all happened so fast. I got to go.
- 記得給我電話. - 我會的.
- OK, call me back. - I will.
- (MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY) - (BOTTLES CLATTER)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HONKING)
(PATRONS GASPING)
嗨
WOMAN: Hey!
出了什麼事?!
Hey! What's the matter with you?!
(HONKING)
快離開, 走!
Go, go, go, go!
(ENGINE RACING)
跪下.
On your knees.
- 我會的! - 快跪下!
- I'll do it, I'll do it! - Get on your knees!
你晚上溜進去, 用艾瑪的電話去做.
You're going in tonight, and you'll need Emma's phone to do it.
繼續走.
Get moving.
我能進來嗎?
Can I come in?
我沒有對你說實話.
I haven't been honest with you.
什麼意思?
What do you mean?
有些事我要告訴你.
There's things I want to tell you that I haven't told you.
(PHONE CHIMING)
關於什麼?
What is it?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
凱斯帝先生.
Mr. Cassidy.
- 嗯 - 加班?
- Yeah? - Working late tonight?
是的,得熬夜.
Burning that midnight oil.
艾登?
Adam?
(ALARM BEEPING)
從一到第五層都失去監控了.
I've lost floors one through five.
我們打開了第二區安全燈.
We've got security lights in sector two.
留在你的位置上.
Hold your position.
保持和聯絡員通話.
Get our IT guy on the line.
(ALARM BLARING)
去第三區前,檢測一下伺服器
Before we move on to sector three, let's check that server.
(ALARM CONTINUING)
我要大樓內所有人的名單.
I want the list of everyone in the building.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
控制中心...
Control...
- 只顯示了一筆操作記錄. - 那是誰?
- I'm only showing one exec present. - Who is it?
艾登凱斯帝.
Adam Cassidy.
(PHONE CHIMES)
來吧.
Oh, come on.
嗨, 這是艾瑪.請留言.
Hi, it's Emma. Leave a message.
馬丁, 去查一下艾登.凱斯帝.
Marty, go check on Adam Cassidy.
收到, 我進去了!
Roger, I'm en route. Come on!
艾登.凱斯帝不在辦公室.
MARTY: Adam Cassidy is not in his office.
媽的.
Shit.
抓住這傢伙,不惜一切代價.
Aii hands on, get this guy! Use any means necessary.
(ALARM BLARING)
沒人.
Clear.
凱斯帝先生!
Mr. Cassidy!
(ALARM BEEPING)
有人在保險庫.
We've got somebody at the vault.
(ALARM BLARING)
怎麼搞的?
What the hell?
喬克.
Jock.
凱斯帝先生.
Mr. Cassidy.
你已經被抓了,不是嗎?
Got caught with your hand in the cookie jar, didn't you?
我... 喬克, 我可以解釋這一切.
I... Jock, I can explain this.
你從哪兒開始的?
Where you gonna start?
我真的沒想到.
I was beginning to think it would never happen.
懷亞特寧願公司倒閉也不肯賣給我.
Wyatt would rather watch his company crumble than sell it to me.
然後你助紂為虐.
Then you came along with your biind ambition.
我們記錄了一切,每一次會面,
We recorded it all, every conversation,
你和懷亞特每一句交談.
every text between you and Wyatt.
你告訴尼克 懷亞特,讓他把公司的股份轉讓給我
You tell Nick he'll be selling me majority shares in his company
否則我就把你們互相勾結的證據交給FBI.
or evidence of your collusion goes to the FBI.
你操縱我.
You manipulated me.
是的
Yes.
你明天中午去Sutton俱樂部,你,尼克 懷亞特,還有我.
You'll be at the Sutton Club tomorrow at noon. You, Nick, and me.
沒有外人,不帶律師,不帶保鏢.
Nobody else. No lawyers, no handlers. Nobody.
讓他走!
Let him out!
天大的錯誤.
Big mistake.
是的.
Yeah.
你在這兒做什麼? 你不應該在這兒.
What are you doing here? You can't be here.
你利用我.
You used me.
很抱歉. 可以嗎?
I'm sorry. OK? I'm so sorry.
你必須走,這裏不安全.
You got to go, you're not safe here.
每件事... 你說的每件事,
Everything you... everything you said,
你做的每件事...都是在撒謊.
every... everything you did... was a iie.
不,不全是
No, that's not true. Not everything.
我想成為不凡的人.
I wanted to be someone else.
(PHONE CHIMING)
你如願了啊.
Now you are.
你成功了.
你知道...
You know...
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
我愛你是因為你與眾不同.
I fell for you because you weren't like everyone else.
艾瑪, 我會把這事處理好的.
Emma, I'm gonna make this right.
你根本不知道什麼是對的.
You don't know what that is.
你把一切都搞砸了, .
Well, you sure messed that up.
我還在想辦法, 不是嗎?
Hey, look, I'm trying, OK?
好吧,你的嘗試結束了.讓我們去兜兜風吧.
Yeah, well, now you're done trying. Let's go for a ride.
瞧,你什麼都沒有得到,對吧? 這都是設計好的陷阱!
Look, you don't get it, OK? It was all a setup!
- 上車! - 這都是設計好的!
- Get in the car! - It was all a setup!
(SIGHS)
對不起,兄弟.
I'm sorry, man.
為啥道歉?
What are you sorry for?
你沒有撞死我, 對吧?
You didn't run me over, did you?
都是我的錯.
I'm the reason for all of this.
問題是...
The real question is...
...接下來我們怎麼辦?
...what are we gonna do about it?
我會以牙還牙 我...
I'm going to use what they taught me...
...摧毀他們擁有的一切.
...to destroy what they built.
(PATRONS CHATTERING)
和荷蘭人交易進展如何?
NICOLAS: So, what's the news on the Dutch deal?
- 不知道. - 他們已經沒有價值了.
- JUDITH: I don't know. - Good, we won't need them anyway.
記得沒請你啊.
Don't remember inviting you.
我的消失將推動整個故事情節的展開.
My going-away party got this whole thing rolling.
這可能是我在你們面前最後一次露面.
I thought it was only fair that I show up for yours.
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
哥達德策劃了所有這一切...
Goddard orchestrated this whole thing...
...誘導你陷入犯罪泥沼.
...to entrap you into committing a crime.
我沒有犯罪.
I didn't commit a crime.
是你做的.
You did.
你的帝國就要毀滅了.
This is the death of your empire, Nick.
你獲得資助的錢我從未碰過,
And you were funded with money I never touched,
是一家我從未聽過的公司給的.他沒有抓到我的任何把柄.
by corporations I had never heard of. He has nothing.
你錯了,他掌控一切.
He has everything.
E-mails, 短信. 他拍下了我們闖入秘密區的畫面.
ADAM: E-mails, texts. He got the break-in on camera.
所有的線索都指向你. 整個事情都是設計好的.
All the dots connect back to you. The whole thing was a setup.
這是怎麼回事? 這是怎麼回事?
What's going on? What's going on?
- 我們有好的情報來做這事! - 你從哪裡獲取的情報?
- We had good intel on this! - Where did you get that intel, Nick?
(CHUCKLES)
太荒謬了.
This is absurd.
(GASPS)
你不能只是...
You can'tjust...
漢密爾頓.
ADAM: Hamiiton.
喬克的老巢.
Jock's hometown.
尼克...
Nick... (GASPS)
米徹姆.
Meachum.
解決一個了.
That's one down.
還有一個.
One more to go.
無論如何你最好是對的.
Whatever you have better be good.
如果這個奏效, 我們等於買了保險可以同時避開
If it works, we both walk away with an insurance poiicy
再多的錢都買不到這個.
no amount of money can buy.
假如不行呢?
Yeah, but if it doesn't?
拿出你的手機. 坐下. 把電池放在桌上.
Get out your phones. Sit down. Put the batteries on the table.
(DETECTOR BEEPING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
聽說你有兩部手機.
It says you've got another phone.
(SIGHS)
- 喔, 不,不 - 發生什麼事了?
- Oh, no, no. - What happened?
沒有信號.兩部都一樣,全都沒了.
I lost the signal. Both phones, they're gone.
能找回來嗎?
Can you get it back?
- 你必須為此付出代價. - 可以,我給.
- You'll pay for this. - Yeah, I'll pay.
我買下你全部懷亞特公司該死的股權,
I'm buying every goddamn share of Wyatt Corporation's stock you own,
只需要掏出40%的錢.
and I'm paying 40 cents on the dollar.
聽起來怎樣?
How does that sound?
我要了,要不聯邦政府也會做的.
I get it or the Feds do.
- 你不會得逞的. - 閉嘴, 艾登.
- You'll never get away with this. - Shut up, Adam.
你不過是個工具,算個屁
You're nothing but a convenient tool, an empty vessel.
我塞滿你一嘴奇奇怪怪的東西
I filled you with piss and vinegar
並告訴你這是香檳,讓你舔乾淨.
and told you it was champagne and you lapped it up.
- 我不會簽這個的 - 那你等著進監獄.
- I'm not signing this. - Then you'll go to jail.
為什麼? 你有什麼證據?!
With what? What have you got?!
喔...
Ah...
好, 好, 好.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
什麼?
ALLISON: What?
- 趕緊簽! - 你已經獲得了一切信貸了.
- Sign it! - You have taken credit for everything.
你什麼都不會得到！ 你這個傲慢的混蛋！
And you've created nothing! You arrogant bastard!
我把一塊被大家嘲諷像磚頭一樣的設備
I took a brick device that everybody laughed at
最終變成一件大家都離不開的東西
and turned it into the one thing that no one can do without.
我有資本傲慢!
I earned my arrogance!
是的!沒有我什麼都不會發生,你騎在我肩膀上完成這件事的!!
Yes, and none of that happens without me! You stood on my shouiders!
現在我騎在你的脖子上了!
And now I'm standing on your neck!
我始終比你棋高一著, 尼克.
I'm 15 moves ahead of you, Nick.
荷蘭人的報價, 也是我安排的!
The Dutch offer, me!
其實我真正的轉機是直到艾登出現..
I strung you along until the only hope was... Adam.
這不可能
(STAMMERS) That's impossible.
不可能?
Impossible?
我建立了懷亞特公司.
I built Wyatt Corp.
賣還是不賣, 你的公司都要完了.
Sell or not, your company is finished.
你做不做都會一無所有
You've got nothing in the pipe, and even if you did,
你已經沒有資金投注市場了.
you've got no money to market it with.
只是百分之四十的股份,總比坐牢好吧.
Forty cents on the dollar is a lot better than jail.
你決定吧.
You make the choice.
滾出去
Now get out.
他喜歡吃老本.
He likes to eat his young.
那是我權利.
They're mine to eat.
是時候回到你原本應該過的悲殘生活了
It's time to go back to your sad little life.
為何如此費事?
Why go to all the trouble?
因為我想看到他碰壁頭破血流. 你走吧.
JOCK: Because I wanted to see him bleed. Go.
不. 遠不止這些, 你不會僅為此而冒險.
No. There's more to it, you wouldn't risk it all just for that.
我告訴你, 艾登,競爭激發創新
I told you, Adam, competition breeds innovation.
當他在公司有了一定地位後,他私欲膨脹 .
With his name on the door, he developed his ass off.
你需要他.
You needed him.
你需要他的創造力,因為他比你聰明
You needed his mind because he was smarter than you.
他做了一個巨大的處理器,還有一部像ZTE一樣的手機
He made a great processor and a shitty phone
他也起到了他的作用,就像你一樣,離開吧.
and he served a purpose, just iike you did. Go.
沒有他你什麼都幹不了.
You're nothing without him.
Occura是真的.能做我說的一切
Occura is real. It'll do everything I said it would.
我不過是需要他的處理器而已.
I just needed his processor to run it.
(CHIMING)
(LINE RINGING)
- 誰? - 哥達德先生?
- Who is this? - KEVIN: Mr. Goddard?
是誰?
JOCK: Who is this?
你真的應該刪了你看過的e-mail.
You should really trash your e-mails when you're done reading them.
我給你們每個人都發了封郵件
I sent you all an e-mail this morning
裏面我用3DPS資料進行編碼鑒別你的身份.
in which I encoded 3DPS-like data to identify you.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
有人一直在偷聽, 喬克
Someone is always listening, Jock.
一直.
Aiways.
(SIRENS BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
哥達德先生.
Mr. Goddard.
哥達德先生, 你被捕了.
Mr. Goddard, you're under arrest.
我會讓你生不如死.
I'm gonna make your life a living hell.
站好,手放背後
Please stand, place your hands behind your back.
耶! 我們逮到他了
Yes! We got him.
你們做了一件大好事兒,小子
You did the right thing, kid.
對你的指控包括欺詐重罪
GAMBLE: The charges against you include felony fraud,
商業間諜罪  妨礙司法  內幕交易......
industrial espionage, obstruction ofjustice, insider trading.
哥達德,你有權保持沈默
Augustine Goddard, you have the right to remain silent.
但你所說的一切都將成為呈堂證供.
Anything you say can and will be used in a court of law.
你有權請律師.
You have the right to an attorney.
如果你請不起律師,法院也會為你指派一名律師
If you cannot afford an attorney, the court will appoint one for you.
你應該知道我剛剛宣讀的你的權利?
Do you understand these rights as I have read them to you?
我把懷亞特和哥達德交給聯邦調查局了.
ADAM: I handed the Feds Wyatt and Goddard.
他們將有很長一段時間看不到明媚的陽光了.
They won't be seeing light for a vert long time.
茱蒂絲和米徹姆得到他們應有的報應
Judith and Meachum got what they deserved too.
而我, 很幸運.
As for me, I got lucky.
因為我的合作所以被聯邦調查局放過一馬.
The Feds cut me a break for my cooperation.
不...
No...
有些事情現在想來其實也沒那麼重要..
ADAM: The things I thought I wanted don't seem so important anymore.
我從錯誤中學習了正確,還有...
I do know right from wrong, and...
...我必須為我長期以來的欺?道歉.
...I'm sorrt it took me so long to act on it.
我只想讓你知道
ADAM (OVER VOICE MAIL): I just want you to know that
我不想做任何對不起你的事兒..
I never wanted to do any of this to you.
我只希望有一天我能處理好一切.
I hope one day I can make things right.
對不起, 艾瑪.
I'm sorrt, Emma.
謝謝.
Thanks.
快!快!快!快!
Go, go, go, go! Go! Go! Go!
快跑, 快跑!
Run, run!
(LAUGHS)
怎麼?
What?
我有告訴過你,你是對的嗎?
Did I ever tell you, you were right?
關於什麼?
About what?
一切.
Everything.
我的意思是.
I mean that.
很抱歉我以前沒聽進去.
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you.
那女孩怎麼樣了?
How's it going with that girl?
她不肯和我說話.
Well, she won't talk to me.
在結束前是不會結束的,比賽終了才知輸贏.
It ain't over till it's over.
你知道我和你媽約會了多久嗎？?
You know how long it took me to get a date with your mother?
多久?
How long?
很久.
(LAUGHS) A long time.
我看起來都比你現在好看多了.
And I was much better-iooking then than you are now.
- 真的嗎? - 噢耶.
- Oh, is that right? - Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
- (FATHER LAUGHS) - (CHILDREN YELLING)
你去哪兒？地鐵在這邊
Where you going? The subway is this way.
我有更快的交通工具,快過來.
I got a faster ride. Come on.
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS)
我以為我們徹底完了?
I thought we were done with this shit?
這是租的啦老爸,我租了一天
It's a rental, Dad. I got it for the day.
哦,真的嗎?好啦,讓我們找點樂子去
Oh, yeah? Well, then, let's have some fun.
一個能讓你不迷失自己的方法..
ADAM: One way to remember who you are...
你怎麼開這玩意兒的?
How do you open this thing?
就是銘記你的英雄們是誰？.
ADAM: ...is to remember who your heroes are.
(TIRES SCREECH, ENGINE RACES)
($ THE BABIES: "MOONLIGHT MILE")
我已經在做這件事了.
I'm doing things my way now.
萬丈高樓平地起.
Building from the ground up.
羅馬不是一天造成的.
There are no shortcuts.
我的天呀,你在搞什麼?
Oh my God, what are you doing?
- 啥?我搞砸了. - 我們有好多事兒要忙的.
- What? I messed it up. - We have a lot of things to do.
- 來吧! - 好吧, 做什麼!
- Come on! - All right, Jesus!
嗨. 艾瑪詹寧斯.
Hi. Emma Jennings.
稍等.
One second.
艾登, 你有客人
Adam, you have a visitor.
嘿.
Hey.
嗨.
Hi.
你這裡看起來不錯.
Nice place you have here.
我的意思是, 為了布魯克林.
I mean, for Brooklyn.
非常榮幸你能來.
I'm glad you came.
一直收到一個創新公司的工作邀請e-mail.
Kept getting e-mails about a job offer at a brand-new startup company.
卻沒看見他們真來找我...
Why I didn't see that coming...
是啊,我們...
Yeah, we, uh...
我們真的需要你這樣的人才.
We really need you here.
你們請不起我的.
You couldn't afford me.
有大量的股票可得
Lots of stock options.
那必須做的更好才行.
You have to do better than that.
沒問題.
OK.
我真的需要你.
I need you here.
讓我再想想.
I'll think about it.
來吧,我請你喝杯東西.
Come on, let me buy you a drink.
你說你對鄉巴佬男孩有好感
You said you had a thing for bridge-and-tunnel.
你說過的. 艾瑪.
Your words. Emma.
至少我應該感謝你考慮我提供的工作邀請?
Can I at least thank you for considering my offer?
($ EMPIRE OF THE SUN: "ALIVE (ZEDD REMIX)")
謝謝.
Thank you.
我喜歡經過那座橋.
ADAM: I like being across the bridge.
有一種回家的感覺~.
Over here, it feels like home.
($ EMPIRE OF THE SUN: "ALIVE (ZEDD REMIX)")